[
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "What is the size of Bihar's economy at current price in 2023-24",
        "answer": "8.54 lakh crore",
        "choices": [
            "8.54 lakh crore",
            "4.64 lakh crore",
            "6.82 lakh crore",
            "9.32 lakh crore"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "Nominal Growth rate in Bihar's GSDP at current price for year 2023-24",
        "answer": "14.5 percent",
        "choices": [
            "14.5 percent",
            "9.2 percent",
            "10 percent",
            "11 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "Real Growth in Bihar's GSDP at constant (2011-12) price for year 2023-24",
        "answer": "9.2 percent",
        "choices": [
            "9.2 percent",
            "14.5 percent",
            "10 percent",
            "11 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "Which economic sector is the hightest contributor in Bihar state GVA for year 2023-24",
        "answer": "Tertiary",
        "choices": [
            "Tertiary",
            "Primary",
            "Secondary",
            "Tourism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "Percentage contribution of Tertiary sector in Bihar state GVA for year 2023-24",
        "answer": "58.6 percent",
        "choices": [
            "58.6 percent",
            "21.5 percent",
            "19.9 percent",
            "11 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "Industry contributing the most in Bihar state GVA for year 2023-24",
        "answer": "Non-Metallic Mineral Production",
        "choices": [
            "Non-Metallic Mineral Production",
            "Food Processing",
            "Cement",
            "Textile"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "How much Bihar contributes in total Makhana production of India",
        "answer": "85 percent",
        "choices": [
            "85 percent",
            "90 percent",
            "80 percent",
            "75 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "What is rank of bihar among states in economic growth in India?",
        "answer": "Second",
        "choices": [
            "Second",
            "Third",
            "First",
            "Fourth"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "According to the Economic Survey of Bihar 2024-25, what is the contribution of Primary, Secondary and Tertiary Sectors in GSVA respectively?",
        "answer": "20%, 21%, 60%",
        "choices": [
            "20%, 21%, 60%",
            "21%, 60%, 20%",
            "60%, 21%, 20%",
            "21%, 60%, 20%"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "According to the Economic Survey of Bihar 2024-25, which of the following is the largest contributor in the GSVA for primary sector?",
        "answer": "Crops",
        "choices": [
            "Crops",
            "Fishery",
            "Forestry",
            "Livestock"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "According to the Economic Survey of Bihar 2024-25, which of the following has the highest growth in the GSVA for primary sector?",
        "answer": "Fishery",
        "choices": [
            "Fishery",
            "Crops",
            "Forestry",
            "Livestock"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "According to the Economic Survey of Bihar 2024-25, which of the following is the largest contributor in the GSVA for secondary sector?",
        "answer": "Construction",
        "choices": [
            "Construction",
            "Manufacturing",
            "Electricity",
            "Gas"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "Which district of Bihar has the lowest per capita income?",
        "answer": "Sheohar",
        "choices": [
            "Sheohar",
            "Sitamarhi",
            "Sheikhpura",
            "Saran"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "Which district of Bihar has the highest per capita income?",
        "answer": "Patna",
        "choices": [
            "Patna",
            "Sheohar",
            "Nalanda",
            "Begusarai"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "How much is the Crop Intensity of Bihar?",
        "answer": "144 percent",
        "choices": [
            "144 percent",
            "184 percent",
            "194 percent",
            "164 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "Which of the following cereal has the highest productivity in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Maize",
        "choices": [
            "Maize",
            "Wheat",
            "Rice",
            "Gram"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "As per Agriculture Census 2015–16, what percentage of Bihar’s total operational holding area is under marginal farmers (less than 1 ha)?",
        "answer": "57.73 percent",
        "choices": [
            "57.73 percent",
            "91.21 percent",
            "76 percent",
            "97 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "The combined share of operational holding area under marginal and small farmers in Bihar is approximately",
        "answer": "76 percent",
        "choices": [
            "76 percent",
            "91.21 percent",
            "57.73 percent",
            "97 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "High percentage of marginal and small farmers in Bihar indicates",
        "answer": "Land Fragmentation",
        "choices": [
            "Land Fragmentation",
            "Large-scale commercial farming",
            "Land consolidation",
            "Decline in agriculture"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "According to the Economic Survey of Bihar 2024-25 what is the per capita income of Bihar at constant price 2023-24?",
        "answer": "36,333 rupees",
        "choices": [
            "36,333 rupees",
            "66,828 rupees",
            "55,424 rupees",
            "38,555 rupees"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "According to the Economic Survey of Bihar 2024-25 what is the per capita income of Bihar at current price 2023-24?",
        "answer": "66,828 rupees",
        "choices": [
            "66,828 rupees",
            "36,333 rupees",
            "55,424 rupees",
            "38,555 rupees"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "Under the Satat Jeevikaoparjan Yojana a livelihood investment fund upto what amount is allocated to a household?",
        "answer": "2 lakh",
        "choices": [
            "2 lakh",
            "1 lakh",
            "5 lakh",
            "4 lakh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "The Jeevika project in Bihar was launched in which year?",
        "answer": 2006,
        "choices": [
            2006,
            2005,
            2010,
            2018
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "What is the Gross Fixed Capital formation at current prices for Bihar in 2023-24?",
        "answer": "4.6 percent",
        "choices": [
            "4.6 percent",
            "10 percent",
            "11.4 percent",
            "5.9 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "What is the unemployment rate in Bihar in 2023-24?",
        "answer": "3 percent",
        "choices": [
            "3 percent",
            "4.3 percent",
            "4.5 percent",
            "5.4 percent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "According to Bihar Economic Survey 2024-25, what is the per capita energy consumption in Bihar in 2023-24?",
        "answer": "363 kWh",
        "choices": [
            "363 kWh",
            "229 kWh",
            "350 kWh",
            "134 kWh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "sheet": "BiharEcoSrvy",
        "question": "Which of the following banks has the largest number of branches in Bihar?",
        "answer": "Public Sector Banks",
        "choices": [
            "Public Sector Banks",
            "Regional Rural Banks",
            "Cooperative Banks",
            "Private Sector Banks"
        ]
    }
]